When I was using CSV files in the web app,
之前在 Web 应用中使用 CSV 文件时
I downloaded them from this website.
是在这个网站下载的
I would choose an indicator that interested me.
选择一个自己感兴趣的指标
Click on it and then go here to the CSV file and download it.
点击该指标 然后到这边选择 CSV 文件并下载
However, there's another way to access the World Bank data via the World Bank API.
不过 还有另一种访问世界银行数据的方法 — 世界银行 API
If I go to a search engine and I put in World Bank data API,
如果使用搜索引擎 输入 world bank data api
I go here to API documentation.
可以在这里查看 API 文档
So, in general, to find an API documentation,
通常来说 要查找某个 API 或 API 文档
it's best to look for it on the web.
最好在网络上搜索
I'm going to click here where it says "API: Basic Call Structure."
点击这里的 API: Basic Call Structure
Essentially, in order to learn to use an API,
基本上要学会使用 API
you need to read its documentation.
你都需要阅读其文档
If you haven't seen this term REST before,
如果你之前没有看到过这个术语 REST
it refers to a software architecture for the web called Representational State Transfer.
它指的是一种软件架构 全称 Representational State Transfer (表现层状态转换)
I'll put some links about REST architecture below.
我会在视频下方给出一些有关 REST 架构的链接
Most modern APIs use this type of architecture.
大部分现代 API 都使用这种类型的架构
If you scroll down,
向下滚动
you'll see there are a lot of examples.
你会看到很多示例
I'm going to paste these examples in a web browser and just see what happens.
我将这些示例粘贴到浏览器中 看看会发生什么
So, it looks like this is returning
看起来这返回了
country information for countries with income level LIC,
收入水平为 LIC 的国家信息
which I assume stands for Low Income Countries.
LIC 应该是 Low Income Countries (低收入国家) 的缩写
This is an example of an XML response.
这是一个 XML 响应的示例
So, by default it looks like the data gets returned in XML format.
看起来 默认情况下数据是以 XML 格式返回的
Going back to the API documentation,
回到 API 文档
you can see here some of the options that the API has
你可以在此处看到 API 的一些选项
and how to format these URLs to make your query.
以及如何格式化这些 URL 来进行查询
For example, here it shows you can filter by date,
比如 这里显示你可以按日期进行筛选
you can change the format of the response to get JSON instead of XML.
可以修改响应的格式 获取 JSON 而不是 XML
So, going back here to the query,
回到这里查询
for example, I can say,
我可以写
format equals JSON and this is the same information from
format=json 这是与之前相同的信息
before but it's just in a different format and I
只是格式不同
personally think that JSON is easier to navigate.
个人认为 JSON 更易于浏览
So, I would stick with JSON instead of XML.
因此我会坚持使用 JSON 而不是 XML
Next over here, I'm going to click on "API: Indicator
接下来 我要点击 API: Indicator Quaries
Queries" because the indicator data was what I was using for my web app.
因为指标数据就是我的应用中使用的数据
But now, instead of downloading individual CSV files,
现在 不用再下载单个 CSV 文件
I can pull the data directly from the World Bank API.
我可以直接从世界银行 API 中提取数据
I'm going to scroll down and look at some of these examples.
向下滚动 查看一些示例
So, here it says,
这里写着
"Request format", and it gives you this example here.
请求格式 并在此处提供了这个示例
If you put in this URL,
如果输入这个 url
it's going to return all of
将返回
the indicators that the World Bank has with information about all of them.
世界银行拥有的所有指标 以及这些指标的信息
In fact, this is actually only 50 of them because I know from reading
这实际上只显示了其中的 50 个 通过阅读文档
the API documentation that it only gives 50 results at a time which you can see up here,
我知道 API 一次只能给出 50 个结果 你可以在这里看到
per page equals 50.
per_page="50"
So, scrolling down, here is an example of getting GDP data for Brazil.
向下滚动 这是获取巴西 GDP 数据的示例
So, I'm going to copy that and I'm going to
复制并将其粘贴到此处查看结果 点击回车
Okay. So this gives me data about GDP in Brazil for
好的 这给出了巴西不同年份 GDP 的数据
various years going all the way back to 1968.
一直追溯到 1968 年
So, I've already read the documentation.
我已经阅读了文档
So I know that you can start adding options to this query like adding
我知道你已经可以开始向查询添加选项了
more countries or showing more results per page or filtering by year.
比如更多国家 每页显示更多结果 或按年份筛选
So, let's do some of that.
我们来实际查询一下
For example, I can add other countries to this query, like,
举个例子 我可以将其他国家添加到该查询中
say the US and
比如美国和中国
China and I know how to format this because I've read it in the documentation.
我知道如何设置格式 因为我已经阅读了文档
I hit "Enter" and if I scroll down, well,
按下回车 如果我向下滚动
it looks like we certainly have Brazil but that's because like I said before,
看起来仍然只有巴西的数据 但是正如我之前所说
it'll only give you 50 results at a time.
因为一次只会给 50 个结果
So, to get more results,
要获得更多结果
I have to tell it with a variable and
我必须用一个变量进行设置
say per page and increase the amount of results per page.
设置 per_page 每页的结果数量
So, now I have 500 results per page instead of 50 and if I scroll down,
现在每页有 500 个结果 而不是 50 个 向下滚动
we'll see that we've also got China here and we've got the United States.
我们会看到有中国 还有美国
So, let's say I also want to return this in JSON format.
假设我还想以 JSON 格式返回这些信息
So, I can say format equals JSON and this is the same data.
我可以设置 format=json 这是相同的数据
It's just in a different format that,
只是格式不同
like I said, in my opinion,
就像我之前所说的
is easier to navigate.
更容易浏览
I can filter by date as well and just get data from, say,
我也可以按日期筛选 比如 1990 到 2015 这就是全部的结果
It might seem like I magically know how to do all of this but in reality,
看来很神奇 好像我都知道该怎么做 但实际上
I've been reading the World Bank documentation to
准备本课程时 我一直在阅读世界银行的文档
prepare this course and looking at a bunch of examples.
并且查看了大量的示例
As an example, how do I know what the country names are?
比如 我怎么知道国家名字代号?
Well, I've read in the documentation that the country names are using
我在文档中读到 国名使用的是
the two-character ISO codes which
两个字符的 ISO 代码
is an international standard for abbreviating country names.
是缩写国家名称的一种国际标准
There are a couple of caveats I want to mention.
有几个注意事项
First, this API does not require authentication or in other words,
首先 此 API 不需要身份验证
it doesn't require a username,
也就是说不需要用户名、密码或其他任何标识
That means I can directly paste a URL into the browser and get the results back.
这意味着 我可以直接将 URL 粘贴到浏览器中返回结果
However, that is not the case with all APIs.
但是 并非所有 API 都是这样
Many APIs require some authentication.
很多 API 都需要身份验证
So, you need to send an API request programmatically, like,
因此 你需要以编程方式发送 API 请求
with Python Code including a message that includes
比如使用 Python 代码 其中包含你的凭证信息
your credentials and API's documentation should ideally tell you how to do that.
API 文档理论上都会告诉你如何执行此操作
Next, you're going to practice making calls to the World Bank API
接下来 你将练习使用 Python 调用世界银行 API
using Python and then navigate the results that you get back.
然后浏览返回的结果
This will set you up for using an API in your web app.
完成该练习后 你就能够在自己的应用中使用 API 了